pizzaexpress-offers.co.uk 2013-05-23

# Privacy Policy - PizzaExpress Restaurants

## Privacy Policy

### 1\. Privacy and your personal data

1.1 PizzaExpress Limited is committed to protecting the privacy of our users and customers. This privacy policy (" **Privacy Policy** ") is intended to inform you how we gather, define, and utilise your Information (as defined below).

1.2 It applies to Information collected by us, or provided by you, whether in one of our restaurants, over our Website (including the mobile optimised version of the website accessible from your portable hand-held device) or our PizzaExpress App, or in any other way (such as over the telephone). It is also intended to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Website, App and our products and services. Please take a minute to read and understand the policy.

1.3 All your personal Information shall be held and used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the " **Act** "). If you want to know what information we collect and hold about you, please write to us at:

PizzaExpress Limited

Hunton House,

Highbridge Estate,

Oxford Road,

Uxbridge,

Middlesex,

UB8 1LX

1.4 PizzaExpress Limited is the data controller of your Information for the purposes of the Act and is a company registered under number 01404552 and whose VAT number is 627 0767 30.

### 2\. What Information Do We Collect on our Website?

2.1 2.1 When you visit our Website (including the mobile optimised version of the website accessible from your portable hand-held device) you may provide us with personal information such as name, address, email address, mobile phone number, date of birth, credit/debit card number, PayPal account information and details about other members of your family who might be interested in our services (" **Information** "). You may provide us with Information in a number of ways:

(a) by supplying us with the Information as listed above, on an individual basis by registering as a Registered User or subscribing to receive updates or offers from us. To become a Registered User you must provide us with your name, address, date of birth and email address, but you may provide us with additional information if you choose to do so.

(b) by corresponding with us by email, in which case we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses; and

(c) by booking a table, ordering a takeaway online using our Click & Collect service, downloading our offers, purchasing a gift card or applying for a job with us; and

(d) through any preferences and areas of interest as advised by you on subscribing to our online services; and

(e) by Information provided when you use our App (see below) and

(f) by Information provided when you use our mobile optimised website from your portable hand-held device including details of your physical location, where you have agreed to it being used.

2.2 From time-to-time we may give you the option to provide us with Information about other people in your life, for example as a Registered User, you have the option to tell us whether you have any children and if so their gender and date of birth. We use this Information to tell you about offers that may be relevant to your friends or family members in accordance with your wishes as communicated to us. We will never use this information to contact your friends or family members directly.

2.3 We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type and the geographical location of your computer, for system administration and we may report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about browsing actions and patterns and does not identify you as an individual.

### 3\. What Information do we collect on our App?

3.1 When using our App, you may provide us with the following Information:

(a) your name and contact details (email address and mobile telephone number), if you use the App to book a table at one of our restaurants;

(b) further information (mobile phone number, date of birth, favourite restaurants, details about other members of your family who might be interested in our services, if you use the App to register as a Registered User or subscribe to receive updates or offers from us. To become a Registered User you must provide us with your name, address, email address, and date of birth, but you may provide us with additional information if you choose to do so;

(c) information which allows us to identify your credit or debit card details or PayPal account and complete a transaction with you, should you elect to pay for your takeaway or pay your restaurant bill using a PayPal account via the App;

(d) your physical location, where you have agreed to it being used for the ‘Find a Restaurant’ feature on the App; and

(e) other Information that may be provided by you when adding content to our App, or to our social network pages such as Facebook.

### 4\. Cookies

4.1 Similar to other commercial websites, our Website uses a technology called "cookies" and web server logs to collect information about how our Website is used. A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site's computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies

4.2 Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Website, and the websites visited just before and just after our Website.

4.3 Cookies, in conjunction with our web server's log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our Website and which parts of the website are most popular. This helps us gather feedback so that we can improve our Website and better serve our customers. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal Information about you and we do not generally store any personal Information that you provided to us in your cookies.

4.4 We use ‘session’ cookies which enable you to carry information across pages of the Website and avoid having to re-enter information. Session cookies enable us to compile statistics that help us to understand how the Website is being used and to improve its structure.

4.5 We also use ‘persistent’ cookies which remain in the cookies file of your browser for longer and help us to recognise you as a unique visitor to the Website, tailoring the content of certain areas of the Website to offer you content that match your preferred interests.

4.6 You can refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the Website.

4.7 Please note that where we feature third party advertisements on our Website our advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control.

### 5\. How Do We Use The Information That You Provide To Us?

5.1 We use your Information in the following ways:

(a) to ensure that content from our Website or App is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer or device;

(b) to allow you to register with us and create a MyPizzaExpress account or order any products and services available on our Website where you choose to do so;

(c) to notify you about changes to our service;

(d) in accordance with your wishes as communicated to us at the point of Registration;

(e) if you have given your consent at the point of Registration, to contact you with information about products, services and special offers that you request from us, or that we feel may be of interest to you or to ask you to participate in one of our customer satisfaction surveys;

(f) if you’re using the App, to send you ‘push’ notifications (where you have agreed to receive them) containing information about our products and services and to facilitate presentation of content of the App.

5.2 We may pass your Information to carefully selected third party organisations:

(a) where this is required for the purpose of supplying the services available through our site (e.g. facilitation of restaurant bookings or ordering a takeaway)

(b) if we buy or sell any business or assets in which case we may disclose your Information to the seller or buyer of such business or assets;

(c) if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions and other agreements or protect the rights, property, or safety of our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### 6\. How Can You Access And Correct Your Information?

6.1 You may request access to all your Information that we collect online and maintain in our database by writing to us at the following address:

Data Controller,

PizzaExpress Limited,

Hunton House,

Highbridge Estate,

Oxford Road,

Uxbridge,

Middlesex,

UB8 1LX

6.2 We are entitled to charge a reasonable fee for this service.

### 7\. Your Consent

7.1 By using our Website or App you consent to our collection and use of the Information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Website or otherwise notify you to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

### 8\. Where we store your personal data

8.1 Data and Information that we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). You consent to our sending and storing Your Information outside the EEA. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 9\. Security

9.1 We maintain the highest standards of security, however the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect your Information, we cannot ensure the security of your data transmitted to our Website. Any information you submit is sent at your own risk. Once we have received your Information we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access.

### 10\. Third party sites

10.1 Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy and Cookies Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which are linked to ours is subject to that website’s own rules and policies.
